Guide to the Academic Council records, 1954-2000 UA.28.03.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Records of Academic Council Committees.
  - Faculty and Staff Housing, Committee on, Records, 1967-1970, 1979
    - Policy and eligibility 1968-1975 (Box 3)
    - Mortgage, lots (Box 3)
    - Park and Playground, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Emeriti Committee
    - Records, 1984-1988, [2 folders] (Box 3)
    - George Maddox 1984-1985, [2 folders] (Box 3)
    - Unlabeled, [2 folders] (Box 3)
    - Nov. 1983-Mar 1984 (Box 3)
    - 1984 Mar.-Apr. (Box 3)
    - Ad-Hoc Meeting, 1984 Mar 6 (Box 4)
    - Final report and correspondence, 1984 March 26 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence with Other Institutes, Fall 1983 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Emeriti Surveys and Widow Responses (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire Responses, 1984, [2 folders] (Box 4)
  - Faculty Hearing Committee
    Portions of the Faculty Hearing Committee materials are RESTRICTED.
    - Transcript of Committee Hearing, 1971 May (Box 4)
    - Dr. Smith, report, summaries, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Dr. Smith Case, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Chair, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - General materials, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Complaints
      Complaint materials are RESTRICTED.
      - Duilio Giannitrapani complaint, 1975-1976, [2 folders] (Box 5)
      - Burford complaint, 1975-1976, [3 folders] (Box 5)
  - Faculty Homesites Committee (Box 6)
    - Unlabeled, [2 folders] (Box 6)
    - Log for Homesite Applications (Box 6)
    - Contractor's Questionnaire (Box 6)
    - New Homesites Development, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - Blueprints (Box 6)
  - Honorary Degrees, Committee on
    - 1968 (Box 6)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Non-Academic Employees Committee
    - Local Labor Market (Box 6)
    - Data on Duke Employees (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Data from Other Universities (Box 6)
  - Research Policy Committee, Code of Policy and Procedures for Dealing with Allegation of Research Fraud or Misconduct, 1989 (Box 6)
  - ROTC Committee, [2 folders] (Box 6)
  - Student Publications, Committee on, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Student Records Policy Committee (Box 7)
    - Report on Policy on University Records, Documents for Parts I and II, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Report on Policy on University Records, Documents for Part III A B C, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Report on Policy on University Records, Documents for Part III D E, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Task Force on Intellectual Life, report: Building Community of Interest, 1994 (Box 7)
  - University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Committee on Women Faculty
    Portions of the Committee on Women Faculty materials are RESTRICTED.
    Additional records of the Committee on Women Faculty were received in 2003. These materials are housed in Box 17 of the Committees Series.
    - 1987-1988, [2 folders] (Box 7)
    - Maternity policy, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
    - Unfoldered (Box 7)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 7)
    - Women in medicine (Box 7)
    - Provost's yearly report, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Interviews, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - Medical Center, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
    - Salary Equity (Box 8)
    - Related Business and Medical Center, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Related Business, 1986-1987, [2 folders] (Box 8)
    - Sexual Harassment, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - Business, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - Unfoldered (Box 8)
    - Medical Center Subcommittee, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
    - Medical Center and Dr. Putnam (Box 8)
    - Unfoldered (Box 8)
  - Faculty Fringe Benefits, Committee on (Box 9)
    - Minutes and Action, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Retirement, 1965-1967 (Box 9)
    - Minutes and Action, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Hospital and Medical Care, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
    - NC Blue Cross and Blue Shield Binder (Box 9)
    - Hospital Room Rates and Charges, November 1970 (Box 9)
    - Medical Center Master Charge Book, July 1966 (Box 9)
    - Handbook (Box 9)
    - Disability Insurance, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - Total Disability, Bevington File (Box 10)
    - Medical, HCA Proposal (Box 10)
    - Medical, PDC Medical Center Proposal (Box 10)
    - NC Blue Cross and Blue Shield Information (Box 10)
    - Unfiled Materials (Box 10)
    - Medical Care, Bevington file (Box 10)
    - General and reports, Bevington file (Box 10)
    - Retirement TIAA-CREF, Bevington file (Box 10)
    - Tuition for Faculty Children, Bevington file (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Richard Harris, "Medicare," New Yorker, 1966 July (Box 11)
    - Charge to Committee (Box 11)
    - Tuition Grants (Box 11)
    - Files of former chairmen
      - Social Security (Box 11)
      - Staff Benefits Booklet (Box 11)
      - Survivors Gratuity and Terminal Pay (Box 11)
      - Supplemental Retirement Annuities (Box 11)
      - TIAA-CREF (Box 11)
      - Travel Insurance (Box 11)
    - Files of Robert Dickens, chairman
      - Blue Cross Blue Shield (Box 11)
      - Dental Insurance (Box 11)
      - Decreasing Collective Life (Box 11)
      - Estes Committee (Box 11)
      - Faculty Lots (Box 11)
      - Healthcare (Box 11)
      - Library Staff (Box 11)
      - Group Term Life Insurance (Box 11)
      - Tuition (Box 11)
      - Menapace (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
      - Appeals (Box 11)
      - Correspondence, Hanna (Box 11)
      - Benefits Changes Approved (Box 11)
      - Academic Salaries, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
      - Correspondence and Material, Chancellor and Provost (Box 11)
      - Reports to Academic Council (Box 11)
      - Agenda (Box 11)
      - Long-term Disability (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Special Study, Files of R. Dickens, chairman (Box 12)
      - Retirement, [2 folders] (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
      - 1978-1979, [2 folders] (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, [3 folders] (Box 12)
      - Special Study, tables (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Task Force on University Governance (Box 13)
    - Letters to Deans Regarding Task Force, 1988, Disk image derived from 5.25" floppy disk. Approximately 0.5 megabytes; 6 files. (Box 13)
      Access Restrictions
      Electronic records in this series have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please select the electronic record link next at the appropriate level.
    - Log, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council Of Arts and Sciences, Members, 1988-1989 (Box 13)
    - Undergraduate Bulletin, revisions and corrections, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Adcock's Handout Budget, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Appointments, Promotion and Tenure (APT), faculty handbook with corrections (Box 13)
    - Professor Barber's packet for review, 1984-1987 (Box 13)
    - James David Barker, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Cable 13/Hoof N' Horn, 1987-1988 (Box 13)
    - Governance Task Force (GTF) Budget material, [2 folders] (Box 13)
    - Committee member schedules, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Letters and Documents from Committee members (Box 13)
    - Correspondence from Faculty to EMM Regarding Task Force, [2 folders] (Box 13)
    - Dartmouth Article Budget, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Dinner meeting Lists (Box 13)
    - FCC report, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Interim report, 1988 April 22 (Box 13)
    - Final Remarks, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Final report and drafts, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Members of GTF, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Responses to Final Report, 1989 (Box 13)
    - GTF Stage 5 Final Report (Box 13)
    - GTF Stage 4 Report, 1988 Dec. 23 (Box 13)
    - GTF Stage 3 Report, 1988 Nov. 23 (Box 13)
    - GTF Stage 2 Report and Addenda 1988 Nov. 16, 1988 Nov. 22 (Box 13)
    - GTF Stage 1 report, 1988 Nov. 7 (Box 13)
    - Revisions of Final report (Box 13)
    - Revisions of Final report from committee members (Box 13)
    - Handwritten notes Dr. Eric M. Meyers (Box 13)
    - Drafts/Revisions (Box 14)
    - Library (Box 14)
    - Handouts (Box 14)
    - Clippings, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Original minutes, 1988 Oct. (Box 14)
    - Minutes and agendas, 1988 Nov. (Box 14)
    - Original minutes, 1988 Sept. 30 (Box 14)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1988 Sept. (Box 14)
    - Minutes and correspondence, 1988 Jan.-April, [2 folders] (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, correspondence, 1988, [2 folders] (Box 14)
    - Correspondence and clippings, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, Duplicates of correspondence and minutes (Box 14)
    - Letters of thanks, outgoing, Fall 1988 (Box 14)
    - Letters of thanks, incoming, Fall 1988 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Subcommittee information (Box 14)
    - Princeton Report, 1976 (Box 15)
    - University Resource Committee, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Proposals and recommendations (Box 15)
    - R. Taylor Cole excerpts (Box 15)
    - Receipts and reimbursements (Box 15)
    - Report: Are Universities Failing Our Society? (Box 15)
    - Responses (Box 15)
    - Schousen research assistant, [2 folders] (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous materials, [9 folders] (Box 15)
    - Crossing Boundaries: Disciplinary Planning for the 90s (Box 16)
    - Trustee manual, [2 folders] (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, [2 folders] (Box 16)
    - Budgets 1985-1989 (Box 16)
      Budgets are RESTRICTED.
  - Committee on Women Faculty ADDITION [A2003-24] (Box 17)
    This material is an addition to the Committee on Women Faculty records in Boxes 7 and 8 of the Committees series.
    - Affirmative Action Plan (Box 17)
    - Annual Reports on Equal Opportunity and Affirmative Action, 1981-1983 (Box 17)
    - Carol Stack, Materials From, 1982, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Correspondence Concerning Diane Everett Payment (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
    - Drafts and Background Materials for Women's Report, September 1983 (Box 17)
    - Faculty Women's Report and Responses, September 1983 (Box 17)
    - Letters on Presidential Search (Box 17)
    - Materials, 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Papers on Women in Academics (Box 17)
    - Profile of Science, Engineering and Humanities Doctorates in the United States, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Reports to Academic Council (Box 17)
    - Salary Material; Salary Equity Study (Box 17)
    - Statistics, Materials From 1982-1983 (Box 17)
    - Statistics on Medical/Professional Schools, 1985 (Box 17)
- Accession UA2018.0044, 1985
  - Special Resolution Honoring Mr. Terry Sanford, 1985 (Oversize-folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Copy of special resolution honoring Terry Sanford passed by the Academic Council. The Executive Committee had copies of the resolution printed for each Acdemic Council member; this is explained in a cover memo accompanying the resolution. Resolution is 17 x 22 inches.